KUNO WOUDT CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL DETAILS

name Jacobus Louis Woudt URL frob.nl

address Mathenesserdijk 304B

 $3026 \; \text{GP Rotterdam} \qquad \qquad \underline{\text{DOB}} \qquad 1976 \, / \, 07 \, / \, 23$ The Netherlands $\qquad \underline{\text{POB}} \qquad \qquad \text{Leeuwarden, NL}$

phone +31 651 255 985 nationality Dutch

email kuno@frob.nl

SKILLS

I am a generalist, full-stack web developer skilled in **JavaScript**, **Python**, **PHP** and **Perl**. When writing client-side javascript I prefer using an MVVM framework such as **knockout.js**, though have many years of experience using just **jQuery**. Server-side I have a good knowledge of python WSGI frameworks such as **webob** and **werkzeug/flask**. For dealing with data I have a thorough knowledge of **SQL**, but also enjoy working with NoSQL databases such as **Redis** and **CouchDB** or extracting data from **XML** using **XSLT/XPath**.

I prefer an environment where automated tests, continuous deployment and distributed version control are used for most projects.

In my spare time I am experimenting with Semantic Web technologies (Linked Data, RDF) and learning functional programming with Haskell.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Feb 2010 - July 2013 / MetaBrainz

Position held: Developer

MusicBrainz is a community-maintained open source encyclopedia of music information. It consists of a website and webservice written in perl, and a fair amount of javascript on some of the data entry screens. The main site uses PostgreSQL as the back-end database and a lucene based search server written in java.

As a contractor for MetaBrainz I was part of a team of three paid developers and a large community of volunteers. I started during a time when we were doing a full rewrite of the musicbrainz.org server software, which went live on May 2011. In the following two years I've mostly worked on the musicbrainz.org server software, working with our community of users and clients to fix bugs as they get reported and add features.

As part of a small team of developers with no system administrators, I was also responsible for maintaining various bits of infrastructure, most importantly nagios monitoring of our servers.

May 2006 - Jan 2010 / COPE

Position held: Developer and System Administrator

COPE aims to provide insight into corporate data. To this end, COPE has developed a generic online survey tool and a tool for 360 degree feedback assessments. My role at COPE was to develop new features for these two products, both generic enhancements of the software and custom features for specific clients. I was the maintainer of the survey tool codebase. Technologies used are mainly PHP and MySQL, with XML/XSLT to seperate logic from presentation, both on screen (HTML/CSS) and on paper (PDF, princexml).

In addition to being a developer, I was also a network and system administrator for a number of machines in a growing network of physical and virtual machines, both colocated production servers and development servers at our office. These mainly run Debian GNU/Linux, with apache, php, mysgl, and other services.

Sep 2005 - Apr 2006 / 4P-IT

Position held: System Administrator

Implementation and administration of a broad range of windows based networks at our clients.

Sep 2004 - Sep 2005 / CSG Comenius Leeuwarden

Position held: System Administrator

Administration of the network consisting of Windows 2000/2003 servers, including Exchange 2003 for mail and both IIS and Apache for various webservers.

Aug 2004 / UPC Nederland

Position held: Helpdesk/Technical Support agent

Providing technical support to clients of a large cable internet provider.

EDUCATION

Sep 1999 - Jul 2004 / Noordelijke Hogeschool Leeuwarden

Bachelor of Engineering, Informatica (Computer Science)

Aug 1997 - Jul 1998 / Hogeschool Enschede

Computertechniek (no degree)

Aug 1992 - Jul 1997 / MBO College De Friese Poort, Sneek

Diploma Elektronica/Telematica (senior secondary vocational education, degree in electronics/telematics)

INTERNSHIPS

February 2004 - June 2004 / Computer Vision Laboratory, Noordelijke Hogeschool Leeuwarden Graduation project

Research and implementation of realtime motion detection and estimation for video games. Various game prototypes and a final game were developed using C# and Managed DirectX 9. The actual motion detection algorithms were implemented in C++, as part of an in-house vision library.

September 2001 - January 2002 / Compiler Technology, Philips Research Laboratories Eindhoven internship

Researching the possibility of extending an existing cpu emulator with support for Very Long Instruction Word CPUs. Part of this project was an attempt to implement support for the TriMedia CPU in a cpu emulator.

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

- Native language: Frisian
- Fluent in English and Dutch
- · Elementary proficiency in Spanish